This is a work of fiction. Names, characters,
places and incidents either are products of the
author’s imagination or are used fictitiously. Any
resemblance to actual events or locales or
persons, living or dead, is entirely coincidental.
To Mizu
Misaki
残酷なる時は いつか
In the end, time unforgiving
契約の地さえ引き裂くの
たくさんが生み出す恐怖
Will draw the blood of covenant
Everything scatters, leaving void
真理のために今ここにいるよ
意外なCrazy
But we're here for the greater good
We Meet
目眩くこのシーン うかつな選択
Crazier than everyone, we need to dazzle
The stage with our careless justice
浮かび行く景色はやがて鮮やかに
And the scenery floating by becomes clearer
時間をすり抜ける
咆筺のメシア
As the Messiah of the Shoutbox slips through time
笑って 泣いて
僕らの一つの夢
Laugh and cry for our one and only dream
願って 叫んで
どこまでも遠くへ
Laugh and cry for our one and only dream
Pray, shout, and struggle right down to the end
走って 飛ばして
気持ちの集まる場所
Pray, shout, and struggle right down to the end
Run and break that place where feelings gather
愛しすぎるこの空の下で
Under this sky, oh so dear
明日を証明したくて
We're fighting for the future
I love giant robots!
「うちらだからこそ造れるロボを」 そのコンセプトどおり
"Build a robot that only we can build."
I believe that the robot we built following that concept is now complete.
みんなの思いがこもったロボが完成したと思います
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流之用 更多中日双语字幕，请登录 www.kamigami.org  台本：卷 　翻译:mam  校对: maize　时间轴：那年夏天  后期：娜夏
Thank you very much!
本当に ありがとう
So...
というわけで
This is Prototype No. 2 of the Let's Build Gunvarrel Project!
これが ガンヴァレルを造ろうプロジェクト 試作２号機
In short, GunPro-2!
略して ガンつく２です
SuperCandy
What's that paper on its head?
あの頭に張ってあるのって 何？
It's the sign of my vigorous resistance.
うちの ささやかな抵抗の証しなの
ロボットに顔なんか いりません
Robots don't need faces.
Its face is the robot's soul!
顔はロボットの命だよ
I believe we've talked about this before.
その件なら 決着はついたはずですよ
それとも 僕を納得させられるような反論ができるんですか
Can you provide any arguments to convince me?
If you can, I'll be willing to listen.
できるなら 聞きますが
こんにゃろ
Dammit!
Hey, Aki!
ちょっと アキちゃん
起動テスト 始めよう
Let's start the activation test!
でも まだ天王寺さんが来てないけど
But Ms. Tennouji isn't here yet.
We shouldn't move the robot without the project leader here.
監督役の人が いないときはロボットを動かしちゃいけないんでしょ
説明くらいなら大丈夫だよ
Let's just go over basics then.
では…
Well then.
オペレーター 八汐先輩
Operator: Yashio.
サブオペレーター 大徳先輩
Sub-operator: Daitoku.
オ…オス
Yessir!
駆動システム担当 古郡
Control system overseer: Furugoori.
But I refuse!
だが 断る
You... what?
こ ことっ…
Just keep going.
そんなわけで 続きをどぞ
試作２号機の最大の特徴は…
The greatest feature of No. 2 is the...
monopole motor.
モノポールモーター これを使っていることです
We are using that.
Thanks to that, we achieved mobility uncomparably greater than No. 1.
これにより １号機とは比べものにならない運動性を実現しました
It is remotely controlled through the Kill-Ballad system.
操縦は 『キルバラ』システムによる遠隔操作です
さすが モノポールだね
Yeah, those monopoles...
まさか あの後毎朝 降ってくるようになるとは思わなかったけど
I didn't expect them to just start raining every day like that...
There is also one more new aspect of the control system.
で それとは別に １号機にはなかった操作が必要でして
それが レーザー光送電装置です
That is the laser-based electric supply.
でかっ
It's big!
A cannon?
た…大砲？
電気をレーザー光に変換して 送電するってわけ
It provides electricity by converting it into a laser beam.
これも カイとジュンの担当だから よろしくね
You'll have to control that too, Kai and Jun.
Good luck!
There's one important point regarding that.
注意点としては 人に向けないこと
Don't point it at people.
ちなみに 人に当たると どうなるの
What if it hits someone?
死にますね
They'll die.
I can't do that!
そ…そんなの無理っ
Uh, that's a bit...
それは さすがに ちょっと…
SuperCandy
Don't worry, there's a safety lock.
大丈夫 安全装置が付いてるから
パラボラアンテナに照準が当たっているときのみ 照射されます
It only activates when it's aimed at the receiver parabola.
Really?
ほ…本当？
カイは こういうのは得意でしょ
You're good at stuff like that, aren't you, Kai?
俺の専門は格ゲーであって シューティングは微妙にジャンルが…
I'm good at fighting games.
Shooters are a different genre...
Sorry for being late!
遅くなりました
Good morning, Ms. Nae!
綯さん おはようございます
I got back a bit too late.
すいません 会議が延びてしまいまして
What do you mean? It's Sunday.
会議 日曜なのに？
ええ…まあ
Oh, well...
それじゃあ 起動テスト 始めちゃいましょうか
Let's start the activation test!
To... victory!
ファイト～ オー
はいっ
Yeah!
こ…こう？
Like this?
よし 発射
Okay!
Shoot!
す…すごい
Whoa...
Batteries... charged.
バ…バッテリー じゅ…じゅ…充填 おｋ
昴 下ろして
Subaru! Let it down!
起動テスト 最終判断を 綯さん お願いします
Ms. Nae, the final order for the activation test, please.
Okay! All clear for the activation test!
はい 起動テスト ゴーです
電源起動 リフトオフ
Power on! Liftoff!
す…すかすかガンヴァレル起動したお
Gunvarrel powered on smooth and clean!
ＯＳ せ…せ…正常に作動中
OS booting up.
レ…レーザースキャナー 展開
Laser scanner on.
ワイヤ 外します
Detaching wires.
さあ カイ 記念すべき第１歩を
Kai, take that memorable first step!
I'll move forward first.
じゃあ まずは 前進してみるよ
よろしく
Good luck.
ガンヴァレル 発進
Gunvarrel, launch!
どう？ カイ
How is it, Kai?
Awesome!
すげえ
Great! It's great!
すごい すごいです
とても 高校生が造ったとは思えません
I wouldn't think it was built by high schoolers!
In the end, I was right about you!
やっぱり 私の目に狂いはなかったです
SuperCandy
However...
ですが…
何？ 綯さん
What is it, Ms. Nae?
皆さんには 来週までに
You must leave this place until next week.
ここから 撤収してもらわないといけなくなってしまいました
SuperCandy
What?!
どういうことですか
What's going on?
会議があったって言いましたよね
I told you there was a meeting, right?
実は ５年ぶりに 種子島からのロケット打ち上げが決まりまして
Well, they decided to launch a rocket from Tanegashima after five years.
そうなの
Really?
And for security reasons, we cannot allow you to use this place anymore.
それで セキュリティーの関係上
ここを お貸しすることができなくなってしまったんです
本当に ごめんなさい
I'm truly sorry!
柔らかっ
So soft!
弊社のパワードスーツは１５年クラッシュの教訓を踏まえ
Having learned from the events of the '15 Crash,
our company's Powered Suits are designed to be resistant to electromagnetic waves.
Berserk Powered Suits Case: In court from the 28th. Exoskeleton, Inc. claims that solar flares
太陽嵐による電磁波対策は万全です
Then how would you explain the Suits going out of control last summer?
では 去年の夏 発生した暴走事故は 何が原因だと？
それについては 裁判中ですので
We will elaborate on that in court.
部長はすごいのか すごくないのか たまに分からなくなりますね
Sometimes I'm not sure if our club president is amazing or not.
万博の委員会に提出する 資料用の映像なんですが
This is the application video that we're to send to the Expo judges.
Aki?
アキちゃん
中央種子島高校 ロボット研究部 部長 瀬乃宮あき穂 １８歳です
I am the president of the Central Tanegashima High School Robotics Research Club,
Senomiya Akiho, age 18.
SuperCandy
巨大ロボットは うちの夢です
Building giant robots is my dream.
巨大ロボットは みんなの憧れで
Everyone admires giant robots.
Giant robots are the heroes of children.
巨大ロボットは 子供たちのヒーロー
巨大ロボットは 正義の味方です
Giant robots are the warriors of justice!
うちは 巨大ロボットが大好きです
I love giant robots!
国会議事堂を襲ったテロ事件以来
Ever since that terrorist attack on the Diet building,
『ガンヴァレル』のイメージは悪くなり
the public opinion of Gunvarrel and robots in general
世間のロボットに対する目も厳しくなったのに
took a turn for the worse. And yet...
ぶれてないんだよ アキちゃんは
Aki knows what she's doing.
ゲジ姉
Sister Centipede!
はい 八汐さん
Yes, Mr. Yashio?
今日の探索場所候補 教えてよ
Tell me where to look today.
はい 君島レポート ナンバー７ 本日の探索の候補地は
Yes.
The possible locations of Kimijima Report No. 7 that you are to investigate today
are the Houman shrine, the Kumano beach, Cape Kadokura—
宝満神社 熊野海岸 門倉岬…
ロケットが…
A rocket, huh?
ゴー ホットドッグ ゴー
Go! Hot dog, go!
カイ あんたも男の子なら ライトスタッフを持つ男になりなさい
Kai! If you're a real boy,
you should become a man with The Right Stuff.
あんなの ただのがらくたよ
That's just a pile of junk.
忘れなさい
Forget him.
Forget everything you know about Kimijima Kou.
君島コウのことは 忘れなさい
ここ数カ月の種子島での「ツイぽ」記録だ
These are the Twipo logs of the past few months from Tanegashima.
I'll look up this Kimijima Kou, whoever he is.
すぐ削除されたが 君島コウの記述が１つだけある
There is one mention of Kimijima Kou, though it was deleted soon after.
発信者は 大徳 淳和 削除の指示をしたのは八汐海翔
The origin is Daitoku Junna.
Yashio Kaito told her to delete it.
彼について調べろと言ったはずだ
I believe I told you to investigate him.
まさか 見落としていたと？
Could you have possibly missed this?
申し訳ありません
I am terribly sorry.
学校の後輩であると同時に 妹の親友でもあるそうだな 彼は
He goes to the same school as you did, and he's your sister's friend.
かばったとでも？
Are you suggesting I covered for him?
If necessary, I shall get rid of him.
必要なら 処分してきますが
I don't know how much of
this to believe.
いや いい
No need.
Mr. Nagafukada's late.
長深田先生 遅いですね
か…帰りたい
I wanna go home.
八汐君は？
And Yashio?
He'd left already when I went to get him.
迎えに行ったら もういなかった どこ行っちゃったんだ…
I wonder where he's—
こ…神代さん 見えてる
Koujirou, your skirt!
昴 見ちゃ駄目だからね
You can't look, Subaru!
I wouldn't! What nonsense!
み…見みゃせんよ ニャンセンスだ
Subject: To Aki
From: Mom
Mitsuhiko called saying he'll be late.
Subject: To Aki
From: Mom
Mitsuhiko called saying he'll be late.
Subject: To Aki
From: Mom
Mitsuhiko called saying he'll be late.
Subject: To Aki
From: Mom
Mitsuhiko called saying he'll be late.
Subject: To Aki
From: Mom
Mitsuhiko called saying he'll be late.
Subject: To Aki
From: Mom
Mitsuhiko called saying he'll be late.
Subject: To Aki
From: Mom
Mitsuhiko called saying he'll be late.
Subject: To Aki
From: Mom
Mitsuhiko called saying he'll be late.
Subject: To Aki
From: Mom
Mitsuhiko called saying he'll be late.
Subject: To Aki
From: Mom
Mitsuhiko called saying he'll be late.
Tsch.
ホントに大丈夫かな
Is it gonna be okay?
I'm just moving it to the side.
移動させておくだけです
もう 次の審査まで 時間がないんですから
We don't have much time until the next inspection.
Firearms arrived in Japan here, at
Cape Kadokura
ここにも ないか
It isn't here either?
Wait, it is?
あれ？ あった
おかしいな さっきはなかったのに
That's weird. It wasn't there earler.
Whatever.
まあ いいか
ゲジ姉 君島レポート ナンバー７に間違いない？
Sister Centipede, that's the seventh Kimijima Report, right?
Yes.
はい ダウンロードしますか
Do you wish to download it?
ここまできたら いくっきゃないよね
Can't turn back now that I've come this far...
ゲジ姉 ダウンロード…
Sister Centipede, sta—
Stop there, Kai.
そこまでにしときな カイ
瑞榎さん
Mizuka?
Mitchie's late...
遅いなぁ ミッチー
ねえ みんな…
Hey, do you think—
Hidaka!
日高君
どうしたんですか 大徳先輩
Yes, Daitoku?
歩くときに ちょっと違和感が
It looks off when it's walking.
違和感？
Off?
When moving, it looks like it stiffens for a moment like this.
足を動かすとき こう…一瞬 硬直ができるっていうか
Could something be wrong with the gears?
モーターのギアが欠けたのかな どう思う？
What do you think?
部長 レーザー光銃座 お願いします
President, please take care of the laser.
瑞榎さん
Mizuka?
I told you not to stick your nose in stuff that's not your business.
言ったろ 余計なことに首 突っ込むんじゃないって
この辺で 手を引いときな
Stop digging any further.
What are you talking about?
何の話
ひょっとして 君島レポートのこと？
You mean the Kimijima Reports?
いいから 黙って 言うことを聞くんだ
Just shut up and do what I say.
それとも 君島コウのこと
Or do you mean Kimijima Kou himself?
瑞榎さん やっぱり 何か…
Mizuka, there is something fishy about this—
Just cut it—
いいかげんにしな…
何さ？ これ
What is this?
Unknown
動かしてくださーい
Make it move!
確かに ちょっと かくんってなったね
It really clicks there for a moment.
Right?
でしょ
Could it be the power supply?
電力不足かな
システムは正常だお
Everything in order with the system.
Keep going on!
そのまま 続けてください
神代さん
Koujirou?
Watch out!
危ない
Unknown
かごめかごめ
Kagome-Kagome...
Who is it?
誰？
Where are you going, Mizuka?
どこ行くんだよ 瑞榎さん
Huh? What?
何
あ…あれ？ 何だ
What's going on?
何だよ この…この
What's wrong with this thing?
瑞榎さん まだ 話は…
We're not done talking!
カイ 悪いけどさ 手 貸してくんない
Kai, could you help me out a bit?
何か こいつ 具合が悪いみたいでさ
It's acting up... It won't stop.
止まらないんだよ
It won't stop?
止まらないって…
瑞榎さん
Mizuka?
Berserk Powered Suits Case: In court from the 28th. Exoskeleton, Inc. claims that solar flares
Then how would you explain the Suits going out of control last summer?
では 去年の夏 発生した暴走事故は何が原因だと…
Berserk Powered Suits Case: In court from the 28th.
暴…走…
Out of control...
瑞榎さん
Mizuka!
カイ
Kai!
What the hell?!
何だ これ
瑞榎さん 電源 切って
Turn it off!
I can't!
やったけど 駄目なんだよ
離すんじゃないよ カイ
Don't let go of me, Kai!
Are you okay, Mizuka?
瑞榎さん 大丈夫？
カイ 助かったよ
Thanks, Kai...
We need to get it off!
早く こいつを外して…
瑞榎さん
Mizuka!
カイ…もういい
Kai... it's okay...
いいわけ ないだろう
No it isn't!
このままじゃ お前も道連れだ
You'll fall with me!
カイ
Kai!
瑞榎さん
Mizuka!
Hey, Kai...
なあ カイ
Mass fainting on the Anemone
Mysterious mass fainting on an isolated ship
もし ミサに会うことがあったら
When you next meet Misa...
アキ カイ ごめんね ごめんね
Aki! Kai! I'm sorry! I'm so sorry!
Tell her thanks for my legs... for this.
足を こいつをプレゼントしてくれてありがとうって…
それはふとした瞬間に
All those unexpected moments
As you mumble on and on
君がつぶやくいくつもの言葉
Will overcome even my standards
それがいつしか価値観さえも
超えてしまうんだよ
In the end
All those goodbyes we said
いくつもの別れを告げ 僕らは
As we climb the stairway to the future
明日への階段をのぼる
とめどなく零れ落ちる雫も
Just as raindrops fall no matter what we do
光が照らすなら この星は繋がっている
Light will always hold this planet together
奇跡のように命が集まって
Lives gather as if by some miracle
Showing the outline of a lively scene
にぎやかな景色は輪郭になる
An epilogue so bright it brings tears to our eyes
泣きたい眩しいエピローグ
The sky painted by the hearts of those looking up
取り上げる思いが
描いた空
The wind blows gently stroking
柔らかな風が吹き
Turning into a new path
新しい道となり
A path that will always
いつだってその道は
Lead us to this place
この場所に繋がってる
Tune in next week too!
What are you doing?
All hail the Robotics Club!